<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Open Topic (new posts)</title>
		<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/c-2177751/open-topic</link>
		<description>Posts in the forum category &quot;Open Topic&quot; - Discuss anything!</description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:00:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14973429#post-5434101</guid>
				<title>Investiture of Wind duration should be 10 mintues: Investiture of Wind duration should be 10 mintues</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14973429/investiture-of-wind-duration-should-be-10-mintues#post-5434101</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 23:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>JaBang</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>3502516</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>As of this post, it is showing 1 minute</p> <p>~/spell:investiture-of-wind</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5432858</guid>
				<title>UA-work: Re: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5432858</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 06:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Heres that UA quick characters: <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/quick-characters-ua">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/quick-characters-ua</a></p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5428686</guid>
				<title>UA-work: Re: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5428686</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 15:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Lets see.</p> <p>1. Thanks for putting Ambuscade up there<br /> 2. Ah, thanks for fixing up wild shape forms, yeah my coding continues to be rather rough, and I sometimes leave the tabs in when I transfer stuff in from the PDF's, ill make sure to avoid those being there in future.<br /> 3. Yeah, I think that would be good, having it as &quot;Guided Character Creation&quot;<br /> 4. I think just listing them in the same bullet points as the subclasses would be ok? Since, thats what is done for the rangers alternate versions of itself (with then its own subclasses dropped in in sub-bullet points)?</p> <p>Thanks for helping with the code and frontpage Fred!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5427605</guid>
				<title>UA-work: Re: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5427605</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 13:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>So few things&#8230;</p> <p>1. Ambuscade Ranger has been added to the archived UA section of the main page.<br /> 2. Wild Shape Forms, I renamed it slightly to druid:wild-shape-forms-ua and cleaned up the coding behind the scenes, had tabs everywhere instead of spaces lol<br /> 3. For the UA quick characters, we can certainly add that to the section for Heroic Chronicle, maybe rename that section to Guided Character Creation or something like that? What do you think?<br /> 4. I'm not sure if or where to add the Wild Shape Forms or UA Invocations on the main page. I'm hesitant to put them under the main class section, but the archived UA is mostly set up for subclasses, not class features. I'll think on that, see what I can come up with.</p> <p>Thanks for all the work NCat!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5427532</guid>
				<title>UA-work: Re: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5427532</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 12:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>And from UA 23:Druid, heres a variant/optional rule to make druids learning wildshape forms have a bit more depth, <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/wild-shape-forms">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/wild-shape-forms</a></p> <p>Id place it categorically along the same lines as the spellpoints rule, but, the Misc section is for published content, so where this would go is debatable</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5427520</guid>
				<title>UA-work: Re: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5427520</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 11:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>For UA quick characters, <a href="https://media.wizards.com/2016/downloads/DND/UA_Quick_PCs_SFG.PDF">https://media.wizards.com/2016/downloads/DND/UA_Quick_PCs_SFG.PDF</a>, Ill leave this one as well for discussion, since I think maybe? we add it, since it fits sorta alongside what the heroic chronicle section is? Though, its not for backstory writing, just for straight character creation. Miscelanious section? Part of the UA section? Idunno, just putting it here to have it be something I can think about i guess</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5427514</guid>
				<title>UA-work: Re: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5427514</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 11:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Unearthed arcana 6: Ranger, which has the Ambuscade ranger, which is a sort of early attempt at the later on seen Revised ranger that we saw later on down the line, with a heavy emphasis on summons. Though, this was abandoned very early on, only ever getting up to level 5.</p> <p><a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/ranger-ambuscade-ua">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/ranger-ambuscade-ua</a><br /> <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/ranger-ambuscade-ua:guardian">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/ranger-ambuscade-ua:guardian</a><br /> <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/ranger-ambuscade-ua:seeker">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/ranger-ambuscade-ua:seeker</a><br /> <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/ranger-ambuscade-ua:stalker">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/ranger-ambuscade-ua:stalker</a></p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5427473</guid>
				<title>UA-work: Re: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5427473</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 10:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Next up with things to add was UA4, waterborn adventures, which had the Krynn Minotaur, which is now on both the regular minotaur race page, and has a lineage page here: <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/lineage:minotaur-krynn-ua">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/lineage:minotaur-krynn-ua</a>, which ill also throw onto the regular lineages page</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5427449</guid>
				<title>UA-work: Re: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5427449</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 10:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thats the eldritch invocations complete. Ill leave discussion about whether to apply that to infusions to something ill think of a little later, or if anyone does bring up their own thoughts on it.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822#post-5427292</guid>
				<title>UA-work: UA-work</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14955822/ua-work#post-5427292</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 07:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Im mostly using this thread as a way to track progress as I go through each UA to ensure we have its contents up on the wikidot (thank you very much cotteneyenoh for the checklist &lt;333 <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist</a>), since yeah, I find having a discussion forum helps with me tracking my work.</p> <p>First up out of order is UA warlock and wizard's Eldritch Invocations, which we dont have, despite having the ravenqueen warlock from said UA.</p> <p>Though, I'm thinking with this, since there are about 60 Eldritch invocations at present on the wikidot, and there are 20+ invocations in this UA, that I feel I'm going to start by migrating the current UA invocations to a /warlock:eldritch-invocations-UA link, so as to better distinguish them, and then link the UA ones in the top of the warlock page, and then someone with front page perms can add them below the warlocks Archived UA section</p> <p>edit: Oh! And this does actually open up the window to creating similiar pages for Homebrew invocations from the list of homebrew creators we list. Same goes infusions too I believe, meaning I might add an equivilant page, since I know that Exploring Ebberon had a couple of infusions in there</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14932960#post-5416425</guid>
				<title>DMG Races: DMG Races</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14932960/dmg-races#post-5416425</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 13:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>With the work towards finalizing and front-page-ifying the new lineages pages, I got thinking towards something I loosely remembered, and, today had found it:</p> <p>The DMG has in it, a bunch of additional, non standard races. These include things such as gnolls, zombies, skeletons and grimlocks.</p> <p>So, I'm wondering what peoples thoughts are towards them, and whether they should be added.</p> <p>On one opinion, they are listed as NPC races, and the book in discussing them describes them as intended to be used for DM's making NPC's (Some of the races on that same list already had player races, but the NPC race version of them exists as a simplified form of them). So, odds are these weren't really made with players in mind (and well, items such as the skeleton have stats such as +1+2-6-4-4 in their arrays)</p> <p>On the other hand, the Oathbreaker Paladin and the Death Cleric are also DMG subclasses, and they are listed on the wikidot.</p> <p>But then, against that argument, is the fact the DMG does go out of its way to discuss these races as player options</p> <p>So yeah, I wanted to hear other people heres thoughts on it. Personally, on one hand, they are race options in an official WoTC book, but on the other, they most definitely do not feel like they are designed for players (as can tell with things like abilities that are +1 to hit all attacks, which work for NPCs, but not players), and they are also sorta hidden in the book.</p> <p>If we did add them, I feel we'd need to go out of our way somewhere to point out that they would be very, <em>very</em> non standard, (probably more so than the homebrew we list on the wikidot even), since I feel theyd need a bit of context to explain them, and I wouldn't want to have a new player who uses the site use them without said knowledge</p> <p>Plus, it does feel aimed at DMs, so it might not match the wikidots usual &quot;player focused&quot; attitude.</p> <p>Yeah, that about sums it up for me. Just wanted to bring them up for the sake of discussion and so as that we were all aware of them if we were not already</p> <p>Oh, if you want to take a look at the races yourself, they're on the table on page 282 of the DMG</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14596844#post-5414025</guid>
				<title>Lineage Pages for MMotM: Re: Lineage Pages for MMotM</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14596844/lineage-pages-for-mmotm#post-5414025</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 06:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Minor note, but should the Verdan and the Owlin not be setting specific races, rather than exotic? Since the Verdan is of AqInc and the Owlin of strixhaven?</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14915840#post-5410782</guid>
				<title>monsters: Re: monsters</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14915840/monsters#post-5410782</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 13:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>That's pretty much been my thought process NCat. I think this has been brought up before for various other DM-specific topics and we've always come to basically the same conclusion.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14725856#post-5408517</guid>
				<title>Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options: Re: Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14725856/unearthed-arcana:giant-options#post-5408517</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Sure thing! Sorry about not linking them in threads, I was attempting to experiment with a way to format collaborative work, though yeah I can see if this is a bit rougher to work with for importing into the site. If I do such a thing in future, Ill remember to put the links onto the discussion forums as well once the work has been completed</p> <p>Welcome back Fred, good to see you. No worries on the delay, everyone gets like that from time to time I think? Its just nice to see you're still out and about</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14915840#post-5408503</guid>
				<title>monsters: Re: monsters</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14915840/monsters#post-5408503</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 03:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I believe the core reasons monsters haven't been added is that, the wikidot is (at least in my own eyes, others here might have a different input) designed with a player focus, rather than a DM one, so each resource here would be something a player might need to reference in game / use in character creation.</p> <p>A majority of the time, monsters are going to be used by the DM, rather than the player (with the most probable exception of Druids and some spells)</p> <p>Admittedly, it is a bit annoying to not have the animals you wish to wildshape/summon be available on the wikidot, but yeah&#8230;</p> <p>Thats sorta the idea behind my own thinking. Though once again, others on the team might have different reasons</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14915840#post-5408248</guid>
				<title>monsters: monsters</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14915840/monsters#post-5408248</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 02:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>lousilver</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>8099718</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I was wondering if there was a particular reason why monsters aren't available here? this would complete this perfect resource.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14725856#post-5403867</guid>
				<title>Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options: Re: Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14725856/unearthed-arcana:giant-options#post-5403867</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 13:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>All these have been added to the front page. Sorry for the delay, just been unmotivated on things lately.</p> <p>Also if in the future could we include links to all the new pages on these threads? Just makes it a bit easier to add them to the main page.</p> <p>Thanks!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14574559#post-5398193</guid>
				<title>Corrections: Re: Corrections</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14574559/corrections#post-5398193</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 19:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Sunburst was listed as a cleric spell in the optional class features in Tasha's Cauldron of Everything, same as Aura of Vitality, Aura of Life, Aura of Purity, Sunbeam, and Power Word Heal.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14574559#post-5397651</guid>
				<title>Corrections: Re: Corrections</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14574559/corrections#post-5397651</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 05:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>ww123456789</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>4709328</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Why is sunburst listed as a cleric spell? for the life of me I can not find out why and I don't know if its wrong or if I'm missing something&#8230;.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14574559#post-5396418</guid>
				<title>Corrections: Re: Corrections</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14574559/corrections#post-5396418</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 02:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Fix'd</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>