<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Auroboros: Coils of the Serpent</title>
		<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14545578/auroboros:coils-of-the-serpent</link>
		<description>Posts in the discussion thread &quot;Auroboros: Coils of the Serpent&quot; - Should we include this content in the homebrew section?</description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:06:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14545578#post-5222687</guid>
				<title>Re: Auroboros: Coils of the Serpent</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14545578/auroboros:coils-of-the-serpent#post-5222687</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 15:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>From my perspective, this wiki serves to host official 5e content made by WOTC to keep it in one accessible location as well as homebrew content that falls under 3 categories.</p> <p>1) <strong>Homebrew created by WOTC writers</strong></p> <ul> <li>Keith Baker's Exploring Eberron</li> <li>Mike Mearls' ThinkDM</li> </ul> <p>2) <strong>Homebrew that was meant to be official</strong></p> <ul> <li>Legends of Runeterra: Tides of Bilgewater (From what I've gathered, it was meant to be a collaboration between WOTC or DND Beyond and Riot before it was removed for whatever reason. I'm unaware of other examples of such content.)</li> </ul> <p>3) <strong>Homebrew with a wide-reaching cultural impact on the DND community</strong></p> <ul> <li>This definition is much harder to define, but I primarily mean Critical Role given its prominence. Few if any DND products match its impact and remain unofficial.</li> </ul> <p>I'm less inclined to include most Kickstarter projects like what you have presented. I've considered adding from projects I've backed or have interest in (Grim Hollow, Humblewood, honestly most projects by Ghostfire Gaming tbh), but I feel like they don't have as much of a place on this wiki as other types of homebrew we've hosted. I obviously don't speak for every moderator or visitor to our wiki (I know some who would prefer we didn't host homebrew at all despite our clear separation of homebrew content from official content), but that's at least my perspective on the matter. If Auroboros falls under either category and I am simply unaware, I'd be willing to add it to the page, but as it stands, I feel as if our effort is better spent elsewhere.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14545578#post-5220945</guid>
				<title>Auroboros: Coils of the Serpent</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14545578/auroboros:coils-of-the-serpent#post-5220945</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 03:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Figured I'd throw this out there, see what everyone thinks. See how this approach to including non-official content works.</p> <p>I backed this Kickstarter a while ago, and they're getting ready to send digital copies of the content out this week. What does everyone think about including this? Raised about $1.2 million on Kickstarter, and based on a campaign run by Chris Metzen (former Blizzard employee who worked on Starcraft, WoW, etc.) back in the 80's and 90's.</p> <p>Link to the Kickstarter: <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/warchief/auroboros/description">https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/warchief/auroboros/description</a></p> <p>Once I have a copy, I can share some of the content on here so people can get a better idea of the quality.</p> <p><iframe frameborder='0' src='https://www.easypolls.net/poll.html?p=621d976de4b0e79a5d056d28' width='280' height='335'></iframe></p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>