<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Errata Checklist</title>
		<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist</link>
		<description>Posts in the discussion thread &quot;Errata Checklist&quot;</description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608#post-5371340</guid>
				<title>Re: Errata Checklist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist#post-5371340</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 15:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Nice, doing stuff like this will be super useful for us keeping ourself organized from here forth.</p> <p>yeah, dm'ing you id say is the easiest way to make it so we can make it so only certain people have editing perms at present? Though, it does make me also consider at some point in future like, setting up a 5ewikidot discord server or something that has a link to such a document, as well as chats to help us communicate in a bit of a less fancy format, though I don't know if people here would want or need such a thing</p> <p>but yeah, once again, thanks very much so cottoneyenoh</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608#post-5347035</guid>
				<title>Re: Errata Checklist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist#post-5347035</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 02:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>put this together a few days ago. not sure how in depth we wanted to go, but for completeness sake i put in a general sheet for every piece of published content (except errata yet cause idk if we wanna put it by item being errata-d or each entry on sage advice or whatever) and examples of how we could do individual items for the Lost Mine of Phandelver and the Player's Handbook. here's the link:</p> <p><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1cyoji01XRn2fm7LPS0CbCSx2x4SGMqmo6sWWsryzn-U/edit?usp=sharing">https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1cyoji01XRn2fm7LPS0CbCSx2x4SGMqmo6sWWsryzn-U/edit?usp=sharing</a></p> <p>i made it so anyone with the link above can make comments, but i think that dming me/whoever's making the complete sheet and them giving editor access would be an easy way to do it, esp since it's easy to see who makes what edits so any vandalism can be easily tracked down, undone, and dealt with. let me know what you think and we should have a good checklist for stuff to do moving forwards</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608#post-5336520</guid>
				<title>Re: Errata Checklist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist#post-5336520</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 08:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Yeah that could work</p> <p>Hmm, vandalism could be a problem, I think in future we could probably create a google doc that's got like, an approved user list of sorts? But comments would probably do the job for now</p> <p>But yeah, a basic google sheet like that would be amazing</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608#post-5334179</guid>
				<title>Re: Errata Checklist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist#post-5334179</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 02:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>id be happy to have a pinned checklist of things to do, either contained in the pinned thread or having the pinned thread lead to google doc/sheets links. only thing i'd say is that we should have any google docs we make be comment-only for anyone but their creator to avoid vandalism (i was gonna say griefing but idk what word best applies lol. basically we don't want people to be dicks and screw up any documentation we've got, but comments would allow the page's creator to review and approve as applicable).</p> <p>i can throw together a basic google sheet with the list of published content as a checklist to make sure we've gone over everything, including UA, errata, etc. i'm not sure how to pin a thread, but i'll either figure it out or wait for fredbob or another admin to do so if it's an admin-only action</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608#post-5328080</guid>
				<title>Re: Errata Checklist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist#post-5328080</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 03:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Errata, eugh, my bad I typed the wrong word, sorry.</p> <p>But yeah, if you have been going through and making sure all the Errata is there, that's pretty good actually.</p> <p>But yeah, a checklist would be nice for us to organize, whether hosted in one of these posts or like, a shared doc or something. The checklists are honestly some of the better tools we have often times</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608#post-5326333</guid>
				<title>Re: Errata Checklist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist#post-5326333</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 23:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>when you say UA, do you mean the Unearthed Arcana stuff exclusively or do you mean including errata? because i've gone through most of the errata and i think i got through everything we host on the site. i've got a list of the UA that's been published if you want me to post it here, plus all of the other published material for 5E if you're interested/if we'd like a running tally of what we have/haven't added yet.</p> <p>regardless, i do agree that having a checklist for wiki changes we want to do would be nice, kind of like what we have when new books come out. (also v glad that wikidot is back, got worried for a bit lol)</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608#post-5317939</guid>
				<title>Errata Checklist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14715608/errata-checklist#post-5317939</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>During the downtime on the Wikidot, I spent some time listening to some community feedback on the wikidot, and one of the things we should definitely get done is to get a checklist of every bit of UA, and then work through them 1 by 1 to ensure everything is up to date with the latest. Hell, if we can just get a list of the Errata, I could probably get that done myself</p> <p>Yeah</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>