<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>DMG Races</title>
		<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14932960/dmg-races</link>
		<description>Posts in the discussion thread &quot;DMG Races&quot;</description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:01:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14932960#post-5416425</guid>
				<title>DMG Races</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14932960/dmg-races#post-5416425</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 13:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>With the work towards finalizing and front-page-ifying the new lineages pages, I got thinking towards something I loosely remembered, and, today had found it:</p> <p>The DMG has in it, a bunch of additional, non standard races. These include things such as gnolls, zombies, skeletons and grimlocks.</p> <p>So, I'm wondering what peoples thoughts are towards them, and whether they should be added.</p> <p>On one opinion, they are listed as NPC races, and the book in discussing them describes them as intended to be used for DM's making NPC's (Some of the races on that same list already had player races, but the NPC race version of them exists as a simplified form of them). So, odds are these weren't really made with players in mind (and well, items such as the skeleton have stats such as +1+2-6-4-4 in their arrays)</p> <p>On the other hand, the Oathbreaker Paladin and the Death Cleric are also DMG subclasses, and they are listed on the wikidot.</p> <p>But then, against that argument, is the fact the DMG does go out of its way to discuss these races as player options</p> <p>So yeah, I wanted to hear other people heres thoughts on it. Personally, on one hand, they are race options in an official WoTC book, but on the other, they most definitely do not feel like they are designed for players (as can tell with things like abilities that are +1 to hit all attacks, which work for NPCs, but not players), and they are also sorta hidden in the book.</p> <p>If we did add them, I feel we'd need to go out of our way somewhere to point out that they would be very, <em>very</em> non standard, (probably more so than the homebrew we list on the wikidot even), since I feel theyd need a bit of context to explain them, and I wouldn't want to have a new player who uses the site use them without said knowledge</p> <p>Plus, it does feel aimed at DMs, so it might not match the wikidots usual &quot;player focused&quot; attitude.</p> <p>Yeah, that about sums it up for me. Just wanted to bring them up for the sake of discussion and so as that we were all aware of them if we were not already</p> <p>Oh, if you want to take a look at the races yourself, they're on the table on page 282 of the DMG</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>