<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
		<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content</link>
		<description>Posts in the discussion thread &quot;Distinguishing non Standard content&quot; - Should the wikidot make better effort to distinguish between content from standard sources and setting specific sources</description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:08:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5160462</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5160462</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 02:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>1) i definitely think that adding the new and updating existing subclass pages makes sense</p> <p>2) yea i'm in favor of removing athas</p> <p>3) i'll probably include the tal'dorei reborn items eventually and add them to the homebrew items page (probably gonna be mostly replacing the original tal'dorei campaign guide items i added). if people want homebrew items like those to be removed, i'd be alright with that, honestly i add them because im adding them to my own personal compendium on fightclub 5e and figure it's worth it to share with whoever else might want easy access to them, especially by keeping them separated from other items by relegating them to a homebrew-only page</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5157968</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5157968</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Im a fan of these poll options, its a bit cleaner than having to have multiple &quot;I agree/disagree&quot; replies to a post,</p> <p>As for the Athas stuff, Yeah I believe it could be removed. It doesn't seem fully finished, and its orphaned. Plus, it doesn't fit the usual standard for homebrew of &quot;must have been from a member of the DnD writing team&quot;. And well, it doesn't super fit with the wikidots usual player centric focus</p> <p>As for Reborn Taldori, we should include them, I'd think it'd be good if we did, since we do host all the other stuff already. Updating the current ones should be treated the same as when we update stuff between books, like SCaG vs Tasha bladesinger.</p> <p>Items yeah, not a whole lot of need, unless we've already set a precident for including them?</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5157389</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5157389</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 20:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Also wondering if we should consider setting up polls for unofficial content and whether or not we want to include it. Just did a quick search and there are a couple sites we can use to embed polls into the forum discussion.</p> <p><iframe frameborder='0' src='https://www.easypolls.net/poll.html?p=61bba094e4b05e2a74f35233' width='280' height='325'></iframe></p> <p>They have a cleaner embedded functionality that doesn't include the website name and everything, but doesn't seem to work on the forums unfortunately.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5157385</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5157385</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 20:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Couple other things we can discuss</p> <p>First, I'd be curious what everyone thinks about updating/adding the subclasses that are going to be in the Reborn Tal'dorei campaign guide. We already have subclasses from the original, Blood Domain, Oath of the Open Sea, etc. So I tend to lean towards just including them all once the book comes out. I'm less inclined to include any items? We've already got the items from Explorer's Guide to Wildemount so I think there will be some overlap there.</p> <p>The second one is regarding some orphaned pages I found while working on updating the lineage pages. It looks like there are some old homebrew pages for the Dark Sun setting that were set up by Chrooo. I know they're not around much anymore, and it looks like they just took a few of the existing races and added different flavor text up top and changed up racial abilities to better fit the setting. Since Dark Sun is not an officially published 5e campaign setting, would everyone be ok with deleting these? Or should we leave them in place? Links are below.</p> <p><a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/elf-athas">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/elf-athas</a><br /> <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/genasi-athas">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/genasi-athas</a><br /> <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/goliath-athas">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/goliath-athas</a><br /> <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/halfling-athas">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/halfling-athas</a></p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5155882</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5155882</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 22:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I wouldn't say it's getting unwieldy, relatively speaking it's an incredibly small portion of the site, not even 50 individual pages.</p> <p>I think it could be discussed whether some of it is appropriate, like I didn't realize the Mike Mearls content was basically just him spitballing on Twitter lol. But I think we've been pretty selective about what content gets added from a homebrew perspective.</p> <p>I also think we should probably examine how the homebrew subclasses are presented on the class pages, but that's pretty minor.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5155215</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5155215</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 03:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>qorinthian</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6517502</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>@cottoneyenoh</p> <p>Regarding the homebrew hosting - the homebrew itself is just getting unwieldy. I'd allow anything officially partnered by WotC as a whole (as a company), such as the Bloodhunter that officially sits on the DnDBeyond page, but I don't think Twitter content from Mike Mearls or DMsGuild content or Keith Baker should make the cut.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5155041</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5155041</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I added cottonyenoh's blurb above to the main page. I also hid the previous message to everyone but members. I didn't want to remove it just yet.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5153661</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5153661</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 03:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>qorinthian, I don't think we run the risk of overflowing with homebrew content just because we host 3-4 popular/WOTC-adjacent homebrews on the page. The only homebrew on here is Critical Role, Legends of Runeterra (which I believe was partnered content between DNDBeyond and Riot Games that got shot down by WOTC at the last minute), and some subclasses made by Mike Mearls and Keith Baker (I personally don't care too much about hosting Mike Mearls' content as it seems to be whatever he was brainstorming during streams and posting to Twitter, but considering there's only 3 subclasses of his on the main page, it's not a primary concern to me). Homebrew has always been relegated to its own corners of the site in terms of classes, subclasses, spells, and items, so someone would either have to be looking for it or go through a lot of hoops informing them that &quot;this isn't official content&quot;.</p> <p>All of that said, I'm in favor of a generic homepage disclaimer like what NCat and I were discussing (maybe replacing &quot;Please keep official content to the top section, and homebrew to the very bottom section&quot;? It's always seemed to be less for people using the site and more for moderators), but making sweeping changes to anything from books aside from the PHB, Xanathar's, and Tasha's seems a bit unnecessary.</p> <p>To go back to NCat's original point (which I assume was prompted by Strixhaven's new backgrounds granting a lot more benefits than any other background), it's not unreasonable to assume that players and DMs will be able to realize by its description that it isn't universally applicable, just like any other setting-specific background isn't applicable to every campaign.</p> <p>Besides, as Fredbob was pointing out, WOTC doesn't seem keen on publishing setting-specific player features (with some exceptions for Eberron primarily) without eventually making it universal through another &quot;__'s __ of Everything&quot;. I believe that aside from adding a disclaimer to the frontpage, our separation races and backgrounds on the front page into &quot;Common, etc&quot; and &quot;Setting Specific&quot; is sufficient considering we're just here to make everything easily accessible to as many people as possible.</p> <p>tl;dr: we can change the tagline on the front page to be a disclaimer about us hosting setting-specific and homebrew content and encourage players to talk with their DMs, but otherwise we're probably fine.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5152576</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5152576</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 22:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Fredbob711</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6144441</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I don't particularly object to any of this, but are we trying to address a problem that doesn't really exist? I know new people to the site probably don't post here or send messages to any of the mods, but I guess I have a hard time seeing this as being a pressing issue.</p> <p>I know the discussion has been had many times about what Homebrew content this site should host, and whether we leave the UA content available after it's been published. I think we've settled on a pretty good middle ground with the HB stuff; we host some of the more popular stuff and don't try and add everything anyone ever writes. UA I see no harm in leaving it on the page. An explanation is present in the Archived UA section of what UA is, but we could try adding it somewhere higher up so it's more visible. For homebrew we can add an explanation on the main page, and each class' page has a short explanation of what HB is before it lists the HB subclasses.</p> <p>Really the only setting-specific stuff are the races and backgrounds at the moment. And I really don't see WotC publishing any more setting-specific subclasses to be honest. There could be some feats, like the dragonmarks, but other than that I just don't see them doing that very often. And my guess would be if they do make any setting-specific subclasses, they'll end up publishing them as core content whenever they do another compendium like Xanathar's or Tasha's.</p> <p>I don't know, it is something to think about, this is just my first thoughts on seeing this.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5152446</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5152446</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 17:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>qorinthian</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6517502</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>That is all a good idea, but I think that may end up creating a little more confusion or work than intended. Because a lot of content is technically setting-specific (monsters, items, etc), it may seem like a lot of the setting-specific options are not &quot;available,&quot; even if a good percentage of them is relatively balanced.</p> <p>I'm more against even having homebrew on the site, since it's definitely not WotC and may get new players confused if they are just skimming the page or arrive at a specific page from a Google search. It will also eventually balloon to a lot of bloat and upkeep and risk turning this site to dandwiki. In fact, I don't even know if &quot;content written by writers adjacent to WotC&quot; (such as Keith Baker) should really be hosted on the site.</p> <p>Ultimately, a homepage disclaimer is fine. We can add specific disclaimers to setting-specific sources that are noticeably non-standard (Eberron, Ravnica or Strixhaven) not as a site-wide overhaul, but whenever an editor gets to them.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5151376</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5151376</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 09:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I think, with spores or artificers, pre-tasha's they wouldve falled into the category of having the disclaimers, but I think making it into one of the big, setting agnostic content books announces that they are designed to work across multiple settings, in most play.</p> <p>Yeah, with monsters of the Multiverse, maybe we could delay adding such changed to races, but I think everything else should be alright to add such a thing in, since MotM wont be affecting feats or subclasses or etc</p> <p>I actually really like that idea of a front page disclaimer. Maybe have the disclaimer note what sources fall into what, so that when people jump through the pages, they can just see a source and immedietly go 'ah, Mythic Oddessy's of Theros', thats usually setting specific</p> <p>So yeah, a simple front page disclaimer, a brief explanation to what sources fall into where and what they are, and that could be enough I think, and it much less work, with a little table like</p> <table class="wiki-content-table"> <tr> <td>Content Type</td> <td>Books</td> <td>Notes</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Core Content</td> <td>Player's Handbook, Dungeon Masters Guide, [ETC]</td> <td>Core content is designed to work in most tables of play</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Setting Specific</td> <td>Mythic oddessies&#8230;.</td> <td>Setting Specific Content is designed usually with a specific world in mind, and may not be balanced for play at all tables</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Unearthed Arcana</td> <td>-</td> <td>Unearthed Arcana denotes play test content written by the developers of 5e. Some of it may no longer be intended to be supported, or be different in a finalized release, consider discussing with your DM before using Unearthed Arcana content</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Homebrew</td> <td>Dread Metrol, etc</td> <td>This wiki hosts homebrew content created by writers for 5E. While written by them, it does not appear in official publications. Do ask your DM if it is okay to use at your table within play, due to its unofficial nature.</td> </tr> </table> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5150900</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5150900</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 18:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>i'm split between agreeing to changing all setting-specific, UA, and homebrew pages to include this and wanting to just have a key/legend/something on the main page clarifying what the terms mean with disclaimers like what you presented.</p> <p>the main issue i'm trying to figure out is how much we'd need to change. adding disclaimers to UA and Homebrew races, classes/subclasses, feats, and spells makes sense to me and wouldn't take terribly long (make a template like you have and just copy paste it to the top of each page). in the same way, adding clarification to setting-specific races, subraces, backgrounds, feats, spells, etc makes sense, but are there any more setting-specific subclasses? it seems like the &quot;update&quot; books like xanathar's and tasha's serve to import things like the artificer, the circle of spores, the college of eloquence, etc into standard play, so should we clarify on those pages as well? and as monsters of the multiverse comes closer to its release, promising updates to 30+ races, is it worth it to make this change now?</p> <p>finally, there's the items. if we're adding clarification to the other pages, we should probably make it universal across the page, but there's a lot of items that come from setting/adventure books, and adding that clarification to every item seems a bit unnecessary given it'll probably be DMs using those pages the most.</p> <p>i think that an alternative may be to include a disclaimer on the front page or in a &quot;reference&quot; page near heroic chronicle like <em>&quot;This wiki hosts DND 5e content that is setting-specific, play-test content, or unofficial 'homebrew' content. Some content found on this page may not be suitable for play at your table. Check with your DM to see if what you find here is a good fit for your table if you are going to be using it in play.&quot;</em> or something of a similar nature</p> <p>it's definitely an important question to ask, but i'm planning on waiting until MotM comes out before I make any sweeping changes to pages</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5150611</guid>
				<title>Re: Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5150611</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>(oh, and side note, maybe alongside a distinguishing note for setting specific stuff, probably one for Unearthed arcana and homebrew content aswell since we host some of that too)<br /> <em>[Content] is play-test content, and as such may not be at the standard of quality of published content. Check with your DM whether it is good to use if you are going to be using it in play</em></p> <p><em>[Content] is homebrew content released by writers who work with 5e, and is not official gameplay content and as such may not be at the same standard of quality as published content. Check with your DM whether it is good to use if you are going to be using it in play</em></p> <p>Or even double ones, such as</p> <p><em>[Content] is play-test content, and as such may not be at the standard of quality of published content. [Content] is part of the [setting] setting, and may not be designed for play outside of its original setting. Check with your DM whether it is good to use if you are going to be using it in play</em></p> <p>or</p> <p><em>[Content] is homebrew content released by writers who work with 5e, and is not official gameplay content and as such may not be at the same standard of quality as published content. Additionally, [Content] is part of the [setting] setting, and may not be designed for play outside of its original setting. Check with your DM whether it is good to use if you are going to be using it in play</em></p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761#post-5150608</guid>
				<title>Distinguishing non Standard content</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14378761/distinguishing-non-standard-content#post-5150608</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>With the release of Strixhaven meaning we will be adding the content from the book to the website, it's had me thinking about the way this website presents content from non-standard settings (partially due to the concerns for balance with some of said content within the book)</p> <p>the current form of the website doesn't do too much really, aside from seperating some stuff on the frontpage, such as 'setting specific races', however with the fact that many people use this website to learn more about the game, I feel the website should take better effort to distinguish between core and non-standard content. Especially since, with the release of Strixhaven, the dev's are basically announcing their intent to have different settings have different amounts of player balance. (Strixhaven backgrounds give a free feat. And for older examples, the Ravnica backgrounds added extra spells to your class spell list)</p> <p><em>[Content] is part of the [setting] setting, and may not be designed for play outside of its original setting. Check with your DM whether it is good to use if you are going to be using it in play</em></p> <p>or something along those lines, just to denote that the content is not usually part of the 'base game'. I mean, I feel like we have a sorta responsibility to try to make the game easier on others, especially others who are getting into the game, since we do run a website like this, and making stuff clear that its not part of the normal should be something we should do.</p> <p>Yeah the sources exist, but if you're a new player, something saying 'Source: Unearthed Arcana 1', 'Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything' or 'Source: Strixhaven: Curriculum of Chaos' is kinda meaningless, if they even do read them</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>