<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Call to all Rules lawyers and contract specialist</title>
		<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14582244/call-to-all-rules-lawyers-and-contract-specialist</link>
		<description>Posts in the discussion thread &quot;Call to all Rules lawyers and contract specialist&quot; - I need help creating a contract with a demon Lord</description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:06:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14582244#post-5244744</guid>
				<title>Re: Call to all Rules lawyers and contract specialist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14582244/call-to-all-rules-lawyers-and-contract-specialist#post-5244744</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 14:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>cottoneyenoh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>5928724</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>yea i'm in agreement with ncat, this isn't exactly the place for questions like these since we're focused on providing players and dms with the mechanical tools for playing 5e rather than helping with in-game issues. other forums are better suited for offering in-game advice, and i'd recommend you ask around there if you need further assistance.</p> <p>(additionally, if i'm understanding your question right, it doesn't seem like there's much of a contract to make? like digging through your question, it sounds like your tiefling/centaur-tiefling/whatever party member needed a disguise, and their patron turned them into a jackalope and said it would be permanent if you/your party didn't get the soul of the country's regent (i'm not gonna touch on the whole bunny girl thing, that's between you and your fellow players). there aren't exactly any benefits i can tell that are directed at you that would entail a contract or anything, and considering the demon is the tiefling's patron, it seems like it doesn't involve you aside from them being in your party. consequentially, because your question neither relates to the rules of the game nor an actual contract, this is probably a problem that you need to solve in-session yourself.)</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14582244#post-5244338</guid>
				<title>Re: Call to all Rules lawyers and contract specialist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14582244/call-to-all-rules-lawyers-and-contract-specialist#post-5244338</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 05:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I don't believe this forum is the greatest place to go to for in-game playing advice, since this forum is mostly dedicated to the running and maintanace of the 5e wikidot itself. Might I recommend some places such as r/dndnext and r/dnd on reddit, or alternatively the GiTP Forums if you prefer a non reddit website?</p> <p>As for your issue itself, it might not fall under the usual expertises of 'rules lawyers' or 'contract specialists', since the issue itself finds itself to be not very related to the rules of the game itself.</p> <p>My personal recommendation is just, dont deal with devils? It never goes well in game, because most stories are designed to have that always play out poorly, so unless you getting a bad deal with a fiend is part of the story you want to write?</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14582244#post-5243766</guid>
				<title>Call to all Rules lawyers and contract specialist</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14582244/call-to-all-rules-lawyers-and-contract-specialist#post-5243766</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 15:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Neon Rayne </wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>7956269</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>A call to all Rules lawyers and contract specialists I need help￼</p> <p>So I’m in a campaign￼ with a soul collecting demon lord, whose primary goal is to collect the souls of the entire party. he already has two￼ and set up my character for a slow burn mid to late campaign collection should I give in.￼ Now I play an aasimar ￼ corrupted by a vampire bite so technically fallen but not if you know what I mean (protector Aasimar damphier hybrid)(Domain of￼ blood cleric rogue assassin) ￼￼ basically a justicar(definitely didn’t spell that right)￼ /temple assassin in-service to the goddess of war soldiers and Justice. ￼and this demon lord is a contract specialist￼. Due to events in the campaign￼ Several of our party needed to disguise themselves due to a quest in which our party needed to enter a foreign country with a severe opposition to magic specifically they employ mage hunters￼￼ One of our tiefling‘s while in my presence requested this disguise from his patron a.k.a. the demon lord who we all know as shade now our tiefling did not specify the disguise other than to blend in and be able to swim so he’s patron utilizing my characters biggest weakness￼ Ultra cute fluffy things temporarily permanently￼ ￼(if he doesn’t fulfill the bargain he remains in this form( Collect the soul of the regent of the country we are headed to who is in league with one of the big bad cults And has escaped my goddess is justice￼￼) Transformed our Centaur tiefling Into a super cute fluffy female jackalope ￼ A.k.a. my characters perfect addiction ￼ so far this demon lord has only requested the souls of sinners and those who have escaped justice So in essence working within the confines of my goddesses (mandate￼? Can’t really think of a good word here) but I think you’ll get my meaning So what I’m asking is to gather my rules lawyers and contract specialists and help me create a situation in which I have a full proof contract ready for the temptation of sad demon lord because odds are He’s going to corrupt the party￼￼￼ And I’m trying to figure out a way to keep my soul my own and pure while still reaping the benefits￼ That he offers￼ My friends I set you this task￼ Do not fail me￼ For I wish to have my bunny girl cake and eat it too￼</p> <p>And on a sidenote I can’t even kill this guy without violating my goddesses tenants￼￼</p> <p>Now even should a party get together with a deity or somesuch to kill said demon lord he is “completely innocent of sin” and therefore I would be violating the tenants of my Goddess by killing him</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>