<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Should the wiki change from Race to Lineage?</title>
		<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14861475/should-the-wiki-change-from-race-to-lineage</link>
		<description>Posts in the discussion thread &quot;Should the wiki change from Race to Lineage?&quot; - Should the wiki change all the Race pages to say Lineage? Also should the pages also change for the stat increases to be choices? Thoughts?</description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:06:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14861475#post-5394207</guid>
				<title>Re: Should the wiki change from Race to Lineage?</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14861475/should-the-wiki-change-from-race-to-lineage#post-5394207</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 13:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NCat</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>6662241</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>This is something actually in the works on the wikidot, it just hasn't made its way to the front page yet (though, it is on the <a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/home:test">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/home:test</a> page)</p> <p><a href="http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/lineage">http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/lineage</a></p> <p>Heres a link to the current iteration of the lineages page. In future, all races will have &quot;lineage:xxx&quot; in their link.</p> <p>Putting a paragraph like that might be a bit much for every page, but putting down that optional rule somewhere in the greater lineage page at some point could be a good idea</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14861475#post-5393681</guid>
				<title>Should the wiki change from Race to Lineage?</title>
				<link>http://dnd5e.wikidot.com/forum/t-14861475/should-the-wiki-change-from-race-to-lineage#post-5393681</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 02:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Josephjj321</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>8083618</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>In Tasha's Cauldron of Everything WotC started to make the change for 5e to have Race change to Lineage for a more of the times wording. Also they are moving to make all the Lineages have stat increases that are choices. What do you all think about changing the wiki pages proactively? I personally have been running my games where the stat increases are choices anyway, but should the wiki reflect the ASI paragraph on page 7 of TCoE?<br /> I think that the Wiki pages should have a paragraph on the top of every Lineage page that says something along the lines of &quot;the ASI, Proficiency, and Languages are optional. TCoE states that you can chose what would best fit your character&quot;<br /> Thoughts??</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>